Finding Aid for University of Michigan diplomas, 1845-1930s, 1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan diplomas 1845-1930s, 1977
University of Michigan.
13 oversize folders 180 items
87394 Bimu C11 Outsize
Collection of diplomas issued by the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was accumulated from different donors.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection was accumulated from different donors.
This assembled collection consists of diplomas issued to University of Michigan students from various departments and colleges. Also included is a sample of a corrected blank form to be used in 1845 if engraved diplomas did not arrive in time.
The Diplomas collection consists of approximately 150 diplomas issued by the University of Michigan, 1845-1934, as well as some special program diplomas and certificates and seven diplomas for other institutions of higher education.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Commencements.
Genre Terms:
Diplomas.
- Diplomas: University of Michigan
  - 1845-1849 (Folder 1)
    - blank diploma 1845
    - Hunt, Charles J. 1846 B.A.
    - Parker, Franklin L. 1847 B.A.
    - Pray, George W. 1845 B.A.
    - Shaw, Horatio W. 1848 B.A.
    - Tenny, Edward 1848 B.A.
  - 1850-1859 (Folder 2)
    - Edmunds, James M. 1859 B.A.
    - Gibbs, Galucia C. 1855 B.A.
      (Diploma reads 1858 graduate catalogue says 1855)
    - Hall, Daniel 1854 M.D.
    - Harter, Matthias 1855 B.S.
    - Jewell, Phineas A. 1859 M.D.
    - Lane, George M. 1853 B.A.
    - Northrop, Byron B. 1855 B.A.
    - Reynolds, Milton 1856 B.A.
    - Reynolds, Milton 1859 M.A.
    - Tyler, Dean M. 1859 M.D.
    - Watson, James C. 1857 B.A.
  - 1860-1869 (Folder 3)
    - Aikman, Robert 1868 M.D.
    - Bates, Noah 1866 M.D.
    - Cheever, Byron W. 1863 B.A.
    - Cheever, Byron W. 1866 M.A.
    - Cheever, Byron W. 1867 M.D.
    - Eddy, Samuel M. 1869 Bachelor of Laws
    - Edmunds, James M. 1862 M.A.
    - Edmunds, James M. 1863 Bachelor of Laws
    - Foster, George A. 1861 Bachelor of Laws
    - Guthrie, James W. 1862 M.D.
    - Jackson, Amzi F. 1865 M.D.
    - Kitchen, Samuel 1863 M.D.
    - McMillan, Dugald 1868 M.D.
    - Nichols, Henry A. 1862 Bachelor of Laws
    - Parks, Benjamin F. 1860 M.A.
    - Pray, George W. 1863 M.A
    - Rose, Preston B. 1862 M.D.
    - Schuyler, Peter L. 1862 M.D.
    - Seymour, Christopher 1869 M.D.
    - Spence, Edwin A. 1860 B.A.
    - Spence, Edwin A. 1864 M.A.
    - Sutfin, Edward I. 1868 Bachelor of Laws
    - Wheeler, Orlando B. 1862 B.S.
    - Wilder, Flavius M. 1868 M.D.
  - 1870-1879 (Folder 4)
    - Armstrong, Samuel 1877 M.D.
    - Ayers, James Nelson 1879 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Baldwin, Albert E. 1871 B.S.
    - Baldwin, Newton 1875 M.D.
    - Barnes, Erastus A. 1879 Ph.B.
    - Brownsberger, Sidney 1875 M.A.
    - Bulkley, Fred G. 1875 Civil Engineer
    - Case, William N. 1873 M.D.
    - Casper, Jason M 1876 M.D., does not appear in Alumni Catalog
    - Chamberlin, Livy 1879 Bachelor of Laws
    - Cheever, Byron W. 1875 Bachelor of Laws
    - Dingley, Charles A. 1876 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Douglass, William M. 1871 M.D.
    - Elwood, Isaac 1870 M.A.
    - Ewell, Marshall D. 1879 honorary
    - Fearon, Robert N. 1873 M.A.
    - Gibson, Elbridge D. 1878 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Goodwin, Fairfield 1874 M.D.
    - Granger, Annie 1874 B.A.
    - Harley, Virginia 1873 M.D.
    - Hubbard, Caroline I. 1875 B.S.
    - Lodge, Albert 1879 Homeopathic M.D.
    - McIlvaine, John C. 1872 M.D.
      (diploma spells name "McIlrain")
    - McKimmie, William 1870 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Mosher, Eliza M. 1875 M.D.
    - Noyes, Henry C. 1873 Bachelor of Laws
    - Pond, Irving K. 1879 Civil Engineer
    - Raymond, James H. 1878 B.A.
    - Reed, Louisa M. 1877 M.S.
    - Salmon, Lucy M. 1876 B.A.
    - Tyler, Dean M. 1875 Bachelor of Laws
    - Waldron, Henry C. 1872 Bachelor of Laws
    - Wells, Frank B. 1879 D.D.S.
    - Wheeler, Levi L. 1874 Civil Engineer
    - White, George F. 1876 Bachelor of Laws
    - Willison, Eugene 1874 Bachelor of Laws
      (Alumni Catalog gives graduation date as 1875)
    - Willson, Theodore B. 1872 B.A.
    - Young, Charles 1877 Bachelor of Laws
      (does not appear in Alumni Catalog)
  - 1880-1889 (Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Edward P. 1886 Ph.D.
    - Barnes, Erastus A. 1880 Ph.M.
    - Bates, Joseph I. 1880 M.A.
    - Brandon, Edgar E. 1888 B.A.
    - Brown, Ralph W. 1881 Civil Engineer
    - Cavanaugh, Martin 1887 B.A.
    - Chandler, George G. 1880 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Clark, Mary E. 1885 Bachelor of Letters
    - Clark, Mary E. 1887 M.D.
    - Clements, Charles 1883 B.A.
    - Cochran, Carlos B. 1888 M.A.
    - Cooley, Mortimer E. 1885 Mechanical Engineer
    - Cramer, Seward 1887 B.S. in Civil Engineering
    - Dunn, Henry E. 1880 D.D.S.
    - Evans, John S. 1883 Bachelor of Laws
    - Hill, George J. 1881 M.D.
    - Hudson, William C. 1880 Bachelor of Laws
    - Jellison, Ernest R. 1883 M.D.
    - Laub, J. Katherine 1884 Homeopathic M.D.
    - Loveland, William L. 1882 Bachelor of Letters
    - McNaughton, Clara W. 1885 D.D.S.
    - Magness, Caroline Ada 1886 D.D.S.
    - Morley, Fred 1886 B.S. in Civil Engineering
    - Perkins, William T. 1884 Bachelor of Laws
    - Pond, Allen B. 1880 B.A.
    - Stoddard, Thomas A. 1886 M.D.
    - Walterhouse, John T. 1882 Bachelor of Laws
      (diploma misprinted "Waterhouse")
    - Whitney, Allen S. 1885 B.A.
  - 1890-1899 (Folder 6)
    - Bradfield, Thomas 1895 Bachelor of Laws
    - Burt, Benjamin C. 1894 Ph.D.
    - Cramer, Seward 1891 Bachelor of Laws
    - Douglas, Henry W. 1890 B.S. in Mechanical Engineering
    - Eddy, Hattie 1893 Bachelor of Letters
    - Eddy, Hattie 1893 Bachelor of Letters in the Science and the Art of Teaching and English
    - Eddy, Jennie 1893 Ph.B.
      (diploma gives name as Joanna)
    - Goldthwaite, Nellie E. 1894 B.S. in Chemistry
    - Guthrie, William J. 1899 B.A.
    - Guthrie, William J. 1899 B.A. in Science and the Art of Teaching and Mathematics
    - Hicks, Frederick C. 1890 Ph.D.
    - King, Elsa 1899 Bachelor of Letters
    - Manny, Frank A. 1893 B.A.
    - Manny, Frank A. 1896 M.A.
    - Miller, Craig C. 1898 Bachelor of Laws
    - Morley, Fred 1890 Civil Engineer
    - Nicholson, Elbert 1895 B.S. in Mechanical Engineering
    - O'Brien, Frank 1894 M.A.
    - O'Brien, Thomas 1899 Bachelor of Laws
      (with note "as of the Class of 1865")
    - Read, Fanny K. 1890 Bachelor of Letters in "English and The Science and Art of Teaching"
    - Roth, Filibert 1890 B.S.
    - Tuttle, Arthur J. 1892 Bachelor of Philosophy
    - Williams, Olney S. 1896 Bachelor of Laws
  - 1900-1909 (Folder 7)
    - Benham, Albert S. 1908 B.A.
    - Manwaring, Joshua G. 1901 M.D.
    - O'Brien, Thomas J. 1908 Legum Doctoris
    - Pemberton, Fantine 1890 two year degree in nursing
    - Spaulding, Thomas M. 1902 B.A.
    - Stroebe, George G. 1904 B.S. in Civil Engineering
    - Travis, DeHull N. 1908 Bachelor of Laws
  - 1910-1919 (Folder 8)
    - Blair, Minerva 1912 M.D.
    - Conover, Charles J. 1911 B.S.
    - Fisher, Leonard P. 1916 D.D.S.
    - Lehr, Clarence E. 1914 Bachelor of Laws
    - Madden, Clyde A. 1914 Pharmaceutical Chemist
    - Messerly, John M. 1912 B.A.
    - Pond, Alan B. 1910 M.A.
    - Rathke, Ethel A. W. 1914 M.A.
    - Voorhees, Sophia 1910 M.A.
  - 1920-1929 (Folder 9)
    - Benham, Albert S. 1926 Master of Science, Department of Chemistry
    - Brumbaugh, Herbert Leroy 1929 Doctoris Artis Medica
    - Cooley, Mortimer E. 1929 Doctoris Artis Mechanicae
    - Nash, Edna L. 1922 B.A.
    - Roth, Filibert 1923 Legum Doctoris
    - Smith, Erwin F. 1922 Legum Doctoris
    - Tuttle, Ruth B. 1927 B.A.
  - 1930-1934 (Folder 10)
    - Hinsdale, Wilbert B. 1934 M.A.
    - Lombard, Warren, P. 1931 Scientiae Doctoris
    - Pond, Irving K. 1930 Architecturae Doctoris
    - Tuttle, Arthur J. 1930 Legum Magistri
  - UM Special Courses (Folder 11)
    - Brown, H. H. 1885 attended a Special Course in Electro-Therapeutics
    - Cheever, Byron W. 1864 certificate for completion of 2 full courses of Lectures regarding Chemistry and Mineralogy
    - Frissell, Seraph 1875 certificate for attendance at a "Special Course of Instruction in Physical Diagnosis"
    - Kellogg, John H. 1874 certificate for attendance at a "Special Course of Instruction in Physical Diagnosis"
    - Macpherson, J. 1881 attended a Special Course in the Physiological Laboratory
    - Macpherson, J. 1882 attended a Special Course in Electro-Therapeutics
    - Seymour, Christopher 1868 certificate for completion of 1 full course of Lectures regarding Chemistry and Mineralogy
    - Tyler, Dean M. 1858 certificate for completion of 1 full course of Lectures regarding Quantitative Analysis
- Diplomas: Non-University of Michigan (Folder 12)
  - Eaton, Ella E. 1872, Artinum Saurcae (?) can't figure out where
  - Kellogg, John H. 1875, 25 lesson course in Physical Diagnosis by Edward Janeway and JWS Arnold
  - Kellogg, John H. 1875, 25 lesson course in Normal and Pathological Histology by Edward Janeway and JWS Arnold
  - Marsh, Theodore D. 1864, 3 years instruction in Gospel Ministry at the Auburn Theological Seminary
  - Patterson, John C. 1865 Bachelor of Laws from the University of Albany
  - Roth, Mrs. F. 1895 Honorable Mention given by the Columbian Exposition Board of Lady Managers
  - Watson James C. 1877 honorary degree from Columbia College for the director of the Observatory
- Miscellaneous (Folder 13)
  - Eddy, Hattie 1893, Bachelor of Letters, Teacher's Certificate
  - Manwaring, Joshua G. 1901, certificate of internship in the departments of General Medicine, Surgery, Ophthalmology, Gynecology and Obstetrics, Neurology and Dermatology
  - Manwaring, Joshua G. 1902, certificate verifying position of house physician in the departments of Internal Medicine, Surgery, Ophthalmology, Gynecology, Nervous Diseases, and Dermatology.
  - Roth, Filibert 1899, certificate of membership in Alpha Sigma Xi
  - Tuttle, Arthur J. 1892, Bachelor of Philosophy, Teacher's Diploma
  - Nixon, Evelyn 1977 Ph.D.